Guide to the Henry W. Broude, Special Assistant to the President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Henry W. Broude, special assistant to the president of Yale University, records
1977-1988
RU 356
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
52.25
The records consist of subject files documenting academics, administration, personnel, and research initiatives at Yale University.
Yale University. President's Office
Broude, Henry W.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-B (YRG 2-B), Records of Yale presidential assistants.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of subject files documenting academics, administration, personnel, and research initiatives at Yale University.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. President's Office
- Records of Henry W. Broude as special assistant to the president of Yale University, 1977-1988; Accession 1993-A-063
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2044
  - Admissions, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Affirmative Action, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 6)
  - Afro-American Studies, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 10)
  - Art Gallery, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 13)
  - Art School, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 15)
  - Association of Yale Alumni, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 16 - 18)
  - Athletics, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19 - 21)
  - Berkeley Divinity School, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Biological Sciences, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Biology, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24 - 25)
  - Boswell, James, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 26 - 27)
  - Budget, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28 - 29)
  - Budget, 1985-1988 (Box 1A, Folder 30 - 35)
  - Budget, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 36 - 44)
  - Budget Committee, 1978 August - 1979 December (Box 3, Folder 45 - 47)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 49 - 59)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 60 - 73)
  - Bursar, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Cable, 1978-1986 (Box 5, Folder 75 - 80)
  - Chaplain, 1978-1988 (Box 5, Folder 81 - 89)
  - Chaplain Search, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Chemistry, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 91 - 93)
  - Child Study Center, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Classics, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 95 - 96)
  - Collaborative Research, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 97 - 98)
  - Communications, 1977-1988 (Box 5, Folder 99 - 109)
  - Communications Board, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Communications Search, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Community Relations, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 112 - 115)
  - Community Relations, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 116 - 122)
  - Comparative Literature, 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 123 - 126)
  - Computer Center, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 127 - 130)
  - Computer Science, 1978-1988 (Box 6, Folder 131 - 136)
  - Concilium, 1978-1988 (Box 6, Folder 137 - 144)
  - Corporation, 1982-1988 (Box 6, Folder 145 - 150)
  - Corporation (cont.), 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 151 - 155)
    - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Budget (cont.), 1985-1988 (Box 7A, Folder 157 - 159)
    - Bldgs. and Gr., 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Deaccession, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 161 - 163)
    - Development, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 164 - 165)
    - Educational Pol., 1980-1986 (Box 7, Folder 166 - 170)
    - Ethical Inv., 1980-1988 (Box 7, Folder 171 - 173)
    - Finance and Adm., 1980-1988 (Box 7, Folder 174 - 181)
    - Government Rel., 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 182 - 183)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1980-1988 (Box 7, Folder 184 - 190)
    - Institutional Policies Committee, 1977-1987 (Box 7, Folder 191 - 195)
    - Investments, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 196 - 199)
    - University-Owned Residences, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Council on Humanities, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - Council of Masters, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - CandT, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 203)
  - Deans' Luncheon Meetings, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 204 - 206)
  - DeVane, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - Development, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 208 - 217)
  - Development (Cont), 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 218 - 228)
  - Development and Alumni Affairs - Search, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 229 - 230)
  - Dilworth, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 231 - 233)
  - Divinity School, 1978-1988 (Box 10, Folder 234 - 241)
  - Douglass Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - Drama, 1978-1988 (Box 10, Folder 243 - 252)
  - Dwight Hall, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - East Asian Council, 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 254 - 257)
  - East Asian Languages Literatures, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 258)
  - East Asian Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 259)
  - Eastern European Council, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 260)
  - Economic Growth Center, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 261)
  - Econornics, 1980-1988 (Box 10, Folder 262 - 270)
  - Electronic Communications Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 271 - 272)
  - Eleven O'Clock Meetings, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 273 - 276)
  - Engineering and Applied Sciences, 1980-1987 (Box 11, Folder 277 - 285)
  - English, 1980-1986 (Box 11, Folder 286 - 290)
  - Ethical Investment, 1985-1988 (Box 11, Folder 291 - 296)
  - Ethical Investment (cont), 1980-1984 (Box 12, Folder 297 - 300)
  - Faculty Club, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 301)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences-Executive Committee, 1980-1987 (Box 12, Folder 302 - 306)
  - Far Eastern Council, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 307)
  - Far Eastern Languages and Literatures, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 308)
  - Finance and Administration, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 309 - 316)
  - Financial Aid, 1982-1988 (Box 13, Folder 317 - 322)
  - Forestry, 1978-1988 (Box 13, Folder 324 - 330)
  - Forestry Search, 1980-1982 (Box 13, Folder 331 - 333)
  - Forty Three Hillhouse, 1978-1988 (Box 13, Folder 334 - 339)
  - Franklin Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 344)
  - French, 1980-1985 (Box 13, Folder 345 - 347)
  - Friends of American Art, 1978-1988 (Box 13, Folder 348 - 355)
  - Geology, 1980-1986 (Box 13, Folder 356 - 360)
  - German, 1980-1985 (Box 13, Folder 361 - 363)
  - Graduate School, 1980-1988 (Box 14, Folder 364 - 368)
  - Grants and Contracts, 1980-1983 (Box 14, Folder 369 - 377)
  - Harvard-Institute for Educational Management, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 378)
  - Heritage Hall, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 379)
  - History, 1978-1987 (Box 14, Folder 380 - 386)
  - History of Art, 1978-1982 (Box 14, Folder 387 - 390)
  - History-Blassingane, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 391)
  - History of Science, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 392)
  - History of Science and Medicine, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 393 - 394)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1977-1981 (Box 15, Folder 395 - 397)
  - Humanities, 1978-1982 (Box 15, Folder 398 - 401)
  - Institute of Sacred Music, 1977-1988 (Box 15, Folder 402 - 409)
  - ISM - Search, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 410)
  - Institution for Social and Policy Studies, 1977-1988 (Box 15, Folder 411 - 422)
  - Investments, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 423)
  - Investments Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 424)
  - Italian, 1978-1985 (Box 15, Folder 425 - 429)
  - Ivy Presidents, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 430 - 431)
  - Judaic Studies, 1979-1986 (Box 15, Folder 432 - 439)
  - Kiphuth, 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 441 - 442)
  - Labor, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 443)
  - Labor Relations, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 444)
  - Language Laboratory, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 445)
  - Latin American Council, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 446)
  - Law School, 1978-1988 (Box 16, Folder 447 - 455)
  - Legal, 1984-1988 (Box 16, Folder 456 - 462)
  - Legal (cont.), 1981-1983 (Box 17, Folder 463 - 474)
  - Legal (cont.), 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 475 - 480)
  - Legal Search, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 481 - 487)
  - Letters of Recommendations (Box 18, Folder 488)
  - Library, 1981-1988 (Box 18, Folder 489 - 495)
  - Library (cont.), 1977-1981 (Box 19, Folder 496 - 504)
  - Linguistics, 1979-1987 (Box 19, Folder 505 - 508)
  - Literary Properties Committee, 1982-1987 (Box 19, Folder 509 - 513)
  - Mail, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 514)
  - Management Operations, 1978-1986 (Box 19, Folder 515 - 522)
  - Material Culture, 1977-1988 (Box 19, Folder 523 - 531)
  - Mathematics, 1979-1985 (Box 19, Folder 532 - 536)
  - Media, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 537)
  - Media Design Studio, 1977-1988 (Box 19, Folder 538 - 545)
  - Medicine, School of, 1980-1988 (Box 20, Folder 546 - 561)
  - Medicine, School of (cont.), 1977-1981 (Box 21, Folder 562 - 567)
  - Medicine - Search, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 568)
  - Mellon, 1977-1987 (Box 21, Folder 569 - 575)
  - Mellon Search, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 576)
  - Minority Advisory Council, 1978-1988 (Box 21, Folder 577 - 583)
  - Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry, 1978-1982 (Box 21, Folder 584 - 586)
  - Montgomery Search, 1978-1982 (Box 21, Folder 587 - 590)
  - Move, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 591)
  - Music, 1978-1988 (Box 21, Folder 592 - 602)
  - Music Search, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 603)
  - Near Eastern Lang. and Lit., 1978-1985 (Box 22, Folder 604 - 608)
  - Nursing, 1979-1988 (Box 22, Folder 609 - 613)
  - Office, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 614)
  - Officer's Luncheons, 1978-1981 (Box 22, Folder 615 - 617)
  - Organization and Management, School of, 1978-1988 (Box 22, Folder 618 - 625)
  - SOM - Deanship Search, 1979-1981 (Box 22, Folder 626 - 637)
  - Organizations, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 638)
  - Parking, 1978-1985 (Box 23, Folder 639 - 642)
  - Peabody, 1978-1988 (Box 23, Folder 643 - 649)
    - Review Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 650)
  - Peabody Search, 1979-1982 (Box 23, Folder 651 - 653)
  - Personnel, 1977-1988 (Box 23, Folder 654 - 662)
  - Philosophy, 1978-1986 (Box 23, Folder 663 - 667)
  - Physical Sciences, 1978-1987 (Box 23, Folder 668 - 673)
  - Physics, 1979-1983 (Box 23, Folder 674 - 677)
  - Planning, 1978-1981 (Box 23, Folder 678 - 681)
  - Poland, 1983-1984 (Box 24, Folder 682)
  - Police, 1978-1988 (Box 24, Folder 683 - 696)
  - Political Science, 1978-1987 (Box 24, Folder 697 - 704)
  - Poynter Fellowship Program, 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 705 - 708)
  - President, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 709 - 711)
  - Report of the President, 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 712)
  - President (cont.), 1984-1987 (Box 25, Folder 713 - 718)
  - President (cont.), 1982-1984 (Box 26, Folder 719 - 728)
  - President (cont.), 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 729 - 742)
  - President (cont.), 1981-1982 (Box 28, Folder 743 - 759)
  - President (cont.), 1980-1982 (Box 29, Folder 760 - 779)
  - President's Office, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 780)
  - President (cont.), 1978-1979 (Box 30, Folder 781 - 783)
  - Printing, 1978-1980 (Box 30, Folder 784 - 785)
  - Priorities and Planning, 1979-1988 (Box 30, Folder 786 - 795)
  - Priorities and Planning (cont.), 1978-1980 (Box 31, Folder 796 - 797)
  - Provost, 1981-1988 (Box 31, Folder 798 - 811)
  - Provost (cont.), 1977-1981 (Box 32, Folder 812 - 815)
  - Psychology, 1979-1983 (Box 32, Folder 816 - 819)
  - Recommendations, 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 820)
  - Religious Studies, 1978-1982 (Box 32, Folder 821 - 823)
  - Renaissance Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 824 - 825)
  - Research Advisory Board, 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder 826)
  - Research Development, 1979-1988 (Box 32, Folder 827 - 838)
  - Residential Colleges, 1978-1988 (Box 33, Folder 839 - 851)
  - Residential-Development, 1984-1988 (Box 33, Folder 852 - 855)
  - Retirement, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 856)
  - Science Group, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 857)
  - Sciences and Yale, 1978-1980 (Box 33, Folder 858 - 859)
  - Searches, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 860)
  - Secretary, 1985-1988 (Box 33, Folder 861 - 865)
  - Secretary (cont.), 1978-1984 (Box 34, Folder 866 - 872)
  - Secretary Search, 1980-1981 (Box 34, Folder 873)
  - Seven Springs, 1979-1981 (Box 34, Folder 874 - 875)
  - Slavic Languages and Literatures, 1980-1982 (Box 34, Folder 876 - 877)
  - Social Sciences, 1978-1988 (Box 34, Folder 878 - 884)
  - Social Thought, 1987-1988 (Box 34, Folder 885)
  - Sociology, 1978-1985 (Box 34, Folder 886 - 891)
  - Spanish and Portuguese, 1978-1982 (Box 34, Folder 892 - 895)
  - Special Programs in the Humanities, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 896 - 898)
  - Sponsored Research, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 899 - 900)
  - Statistics, 1978-1982 (Box 34, Folder 901 - 903)
  - Student Recommendations, 1978-1980 (Box 34, Folder 905 - 906)
  - Summer Programs, 1978-1988 (Box 34, Folder 907 - 916)
  - Surveys, 1981-1983 (Box 34, Folder 917 - 918)
  - Tanner, 1987-1988 (Box 34, Folder 919)
  - Task Force, 1979-1983 (Box 35, Folder 920 - 924)
  - Telephones, 1978-1988 (Box 35, Folder 925 - 931)
  - Tobin Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 35, Folder 932)
  - Treasurer's Office, 1978-1979 (Box 35, Folder 933)
  - University Council, 1977-1988 (Box 35, Folder 934 - 948)
  - University Council Committees
    - Architecture, 1978-1985 (Box 36, Folder 949 - 953)
    - Art Gallery and British Art Center, 1979-1986 (Box 36, Folder 954 - 959)
    - Art School, 1978-1986 (Box 36, Folder 960 - 963)
    - Athletics, 1978-1987 (Box 36, Folder 964 - 969)
    - Biological Sciences, 1977-1985 (Box 36, Folder 970 - 975)
    - Communications, 1982-1987 (Box 36, Folder 976 - 979)
    - Community Relations, 1978-1985 (Box 36, Folder 980 - 983)
    - Divinity School, 1979-1987 (Box 36, Folder 987 - 991)
    - Drama, 1979-1987 (Box 36, Folder 992 - 997)
    - Forestry and Environmental Studies, 1979-1986 (Box 36, Folder 998 - 1002)
    - Graduate School, 1977-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1003 - 1009)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1010)
    - Humanities-Foreign Languages and Area Studies, 1977-1983 (Box 36, Folder 1011 - 1014)
    - Humanities-Historical, 1975-1985 (Box 36, Folder 1015 - 1021)
    - Humanities-Literature, 1978-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1022 - 1026)
    - Institute of Sacred Music, 1984-1987 (Box 36, Folder 1027 - 1029)
    - Law School, 1978-1985 (Box 36, Folder 1030 - 1034)
    - Library, 1977-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1035 - 1041)
    - Medical Affairs, 1979-1987 (Box 36, Folder 1042 - 1048)
    - Mid-Career and Continuing Education, 1982-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1049 - 1051)
    - Music, 1978-1987 (Box 36, Folder 1052 - 1059)
    - Nonacademic Management, 1978-1982 (Box 36, Folder 1060 - 1063)
    - Part-Time and Mid-Career Program, 1978-1980 (Box 36, Folder 1064 - 1065)
    - Peabody Museum, 1979-1983 (Box 36, Folder 1066 - 1069)
    - Philosophy-Linguistics, 1979-1980 (Box 36, Folder 1070)
    - Physical Sciences and Eng., 1978-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1071 - 1076)
    - Religious Life, 1984-1987 (Box 36, Folder 1077 - 1079)
    - School of Organization and Management, 1978-1985 (Box 36, Folder 1080 - 1083)
    - Social Sciences, 1985-1987 (Box 36, Folder 1084 - 1085)
    - Social Sciences-Behavioral, 1978-1986 (Box 36, Folder 1086 - 1091)
    - Social Sciences-Policy, 1977-1985 (Box 36, Folder 1092 - 1098)
    - Writing, 1985-1986 (Box 37, Folder 1099)
    - Yale College, 1978-1987 (Box 37, Folder 1100 - 1106)
  - University Health Services, 1978-1988 (Box 37, Folder 1107 - 1116)
  - University Press, 1977-1988 (Box 37, Folder 1117 - 1129)
  - University Tribunal, 1977-1988 (Box 38, Folder 1130 - 1138)
  - Veronis Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 38, Folder 1139 - 1140)
  - Vice President-Administration, 1984-1988 (Box 38, Folder 1141 - 1143)
  - Vice President-Finance, 1986-1988 (Box 38, Folder 1144 - 1148)
  - Vice President-Finance (cont.), 1977-1986 (Box 39, Folder 1149 - 1152)
  - Vice President Search, 1986-1987 (Box 39, Folder 1153)
  - Vice President-Finance and Administration Search, 1982-1983 (Box 39, Folder 1154)
  - Vita, 1977-1988 (Box 39, Folder 1155 - 1166)
  - Whitney Humanities Center, 1987-1988 (Box 39, Folder 1169)
  - Women's Studies, 1980-1981 (Box 39, Folder 1170)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1978-1987 (Box 39, Folder 1171 - 1175)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine Search, 1978-1979 (Box 39, Folder 1176 - 1177)
  - Yale Alumni Publications, 1978-1981 (Box 39, Folder 1178 - 1180)
  - Yale-China Association, 1980-1981 (Box 39, Folder 1181)
  - Yale College, 1987-1988 (Box 39, Folder 1182 - 1183)
  - Yale College (cont.), 1981-1987 (Box 40, Folder 1184 - 1195)
  - Yale College (cont.), 1978-1982 (Box 41, Folder 1196 - 1208)
  - Yale College Council, 1978-1981 (Box 41, Folder 1209 - 1211)
  - Yale Library Associates, 1979-1980 (Box 41, Folder 1212)
  - Yale Medal, 1978-1988 (Box 41, Folder 1213 - 1220)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital, 1979-1980 (Box 41, Folder 1221)
  - Yale-New Haven Medical Center, 1978-1980 (Box 41, Folder 1222 - 1223)
  - Yale Psychiatric Institute, 1977-1980 (Box 41, Folder 1224 - 1226)
  - Yale Review, 1978-1985 (Box 41, Folder 1227 - 1231)